Hi. I'm Seungwon Kim.
I am going to share with you my theories and techniques on forward stance carving.
I plan to make 5 ~ 10 YouTube clips
easy to understand for self-taught borders.
I will try to make it easy to understand and follow.
Hopefully you will like it.
I have one thing to tell you.
Forward stance carving theories don't have a long history,
So the way to explain and riding skills may vary with different instructors.
I totally respect each riders' skills.
For 15 years of snowboard riding
I have studied the theory and practiced by myself.
I am not saying mine is totally right.
If you have a someone who is teaching you
trust him/her and follow what they are saying.
The best guide is who teaches by you.
Thank you.
First let's set up the equipment.
Many people miss importance of proper equipment setup.
If you just copy the binding stance of your friend or a rider you like,
the angles/stance might not match your body physique and can cause injury.
When you practice beginner level skills like basic carving, etc.
wrong binding setup will disturb your training.
I am going to show you how to set up the equipment
to make your practice better.
First you should set up the stance.
There is no one proper stance.
The width depends on your style.
There are two approaches.
1. The stance depends mostly on your height.
The width should be roughly equal to the distance
from the middle of your kneecap to the ground.
2. Pick a proper snowboard on your height and set up the default stance
In my case it is 54-55 cm from toe to my knee.
My snowboard is 163 cm.
Default stance width is 54 cm for this snowboard.
As you can see make the stance width up to your knee
from toe or follow the default stance. It will be similar.
If you have a rider or style what you want to follow
you can make it narrower or wider base on their setting.
Lets discuss strong and weak points of each stance width.
The strong points of wide stance is it's easiness to control weight shift.
When your stance is narrow
in case of resistance from the nose,
your weight shifts to the front.
Due to stance being narrow it becomes hard to control weight shift.
(you might be pushed too far forward)
The wide stance will enable you to block the shift of weight with both your legs like this.
It's easier to control the weight shift.
Then it is a similar context.
Beginners often have issues with heel side chattering.
(more on that in detail later on).
One of the solutions to heel side chatter is stretching out your front leg.
Stretching out the front leg assists in uncontrolled forward weight shifts.
Basically you should ride inclined backwards.
When the stance is too narrow for you,
even though your front leg is stretched
in case of nose drag you still might be pushed forward uncontrollably.
So the wider stance has benefits.
Now let's discuss the benefits of narrow stance.
Narrow stance is in the center of the board.
Your weight is focused on the middle of the board making it easier to bend the board
Board being bent more makes smaller turns
The stronger press the more dynamic turn
Narrow stance also helps the rider to rotate his/hers pelvis.
In case of wide stance like this
when you try to twist your pelvis
it is hard to move like this.
Narrowing the stance makes it easy to move your pelvis.
If you are not skilled in the pelvis rotation,
make your stance narrow.
It will be helpful to you.
The next step is setting up the angles of the bindings.
Setting up the bindings' angles is really important.
People who ride in duck stance and enjoy trick or sliding turns.
They still want to try those.
It is quite hard for them to make forward riding stance.
To ride in forward stance
it is necessary to set up the binding angle drastic.
Because the duck stance make it hard to rotate the pelvis.
When the riders in duck stance try pelvis rotation
there is wide gap between two legs.
It can't ride well.
I strongly recommend setting up the stance drastic.
If you want to try trick
or have difficulty sliding turn
change the angle little by little.
How to set up the front foot?
Just follow your role model rider or your friend's.
(more than end of 30 degree)
You can copy mine. (42 or 45 degree)
The rear foot is pretty important.
The setting depends on your flexibility.
Start with 15 degrees less than the front foot.
Fix the binding.
Then put your knees together.
When you make your knees close
A gap which a hand can pass through is the best.
Do not apply pressure.
Do not make it tight.
Just put your knees together slightly.
I suggest the distance with slight gap.
Of course there are various riding styles.
Some people push the rear knee bit more like this.
Some people put the knees wide like this.
In my case setting I set up the distance with slight gap between two knees.
Ah! If your boots are big, I mean you have big feet
when you set up the rear foot based on your flexibility
it can cause boot out.
Set up your rear foot so the boot out doesn't occur.
Let's set up the highbacks now.
We're interested in highback rotation.
The setting of front foot is clockwise direction.
It is better to rotate clockwise as much as possible.
(on regular stance)
Because you need to stretch your front leg a lot
when you begin hillside turn.
Highback covering the inner side of the calf
makes it hard to stretch the front leg.
Some riders cut out the highback before.
There are low-backs like shorter high-backs.
There is reason.
It restricts stretching the front leg.
For the rear foot I keep the default highback setting with no rotation.
Some people say to do the highback rotation counterclockwise,
while others say to do the highback rotation counterclockwise.
The reason is that if you do it counterclockwise (for regular rider),
when you rotate the pelvis,
you can get ?little? sit properly on rear leg axis
because you press the calf.
And if you do it clockwise, when you do the pelvic rotation
and turn the edge over,
you can be easier to turn the edge over
by holding the left side properly.
There are people who say,
"Do it clockwise" or "Do it counterclockwise"
because there are pros and cons,
I think both of them are important,
so I prefer to use them as the basic setting value.
Then, "Highback forward lean" refers to leaning forward.
In the case of this as I said before,
I don't do forward lean to make the front leg stretch out properly.
For the rear foot, when you first do it, you can setup without leaning.
or you can set it to lean one or two step.
If you feel uncomfortable doing basic carving later with forward lean
just remove the lean and start practicing.
If you ride well later, when you feel like getting bouncing when you do heel side carve,
or when you think it's hard to get edge angle,
you can lean highback little by little.
For a novice, when doing basic carving or some basic practice afterwards,
it is comfortable without leaning the highback.
And finally, I'd like to talk about matching binding centering.
When you match the centering
most people put the binding disc like this.
When you look at a deck like this, it's normal to put it in 11 characters.
Sometimes, some people put it horizontally
in order to set the stance width exactly as they want.
Of course, it doesn't matter
if the boot's centering is exactly right when you put it horizontally,
but I recommend that you put it in 11 characters to make it more accurate.
You can change the binding later,
or you can change your boots,
and then maybe the centering will go wrong.
Because of that, you can just put it in 11.
Even if stance width is not the setting you want,
just use it nearby.
I recommend that you use the centering in more detail and accurately.
So far, we've been looking at setting up equipment.
As you can see, setting up the equipment according to your body is crucial,
so that you don't have to miss the practice due to the equipment.